Finding Aid for the Kenneth Rexroth Papers LSC.0175
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kenneth Rexroth papers
1853-1986
1950-1975
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rexroth, Kenneth
LSC.0175
77.0 Linear Feet (154 boxes and 5 oversize boxes)
Kenneth Rexroth (1905-1982) was an author, critic, poet, teacher, translator and active member of San Francisco's cultural, political, and poetry scenes from the 1930s through the 1960s. The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, and ephemera by and about Rexroth, and members of his circle.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio materials. Audio materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Kenneth Rexroth, 1964-1968.
Gift from New Directions, 1970-1982.
Gift from Joseph S. Handler (Series 2, the Esther Handler papers), 2004.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9927230773606533
Biography
Born December 22, 1905 in South Bend, Indiana; campaigned for many radical groups, particularly the Wobblies (Industrial Workers of the World), and espoused eroticism and general anarchy; influenced by poet William Carlos Williams and the Second Chicago Renaissance; founded San Francisco Poetry Center with Lawrence Ferlinghetti and Allen Ginsberg; although his Bohemian lifestyle was emulated by Beats, he did not like the movement for its artistic excess and lack of rigor; noted as an accomplished painter with one-man shows throughout the world; translated poems from the Chinese and Japanese languages; died June 6, 1982 in Montecito, California.
Expanded Biographical Narrative
Kenneth Rexroth (22 Dec. 1905- 6 June 1982) was born in Southwest Indiana. His family lived in various Midwestern cities until he was orphaned in 1919, and moved in with an aunt in Chicago. Rexroth pursued a vigorous self-education while working odd jobs, backpacking across the country, and writing poetry; his early work was strongly influenced by Chicago's Second Renaissance. He married Andrée Schafer in 1927, and the couple moved to San Francisco. During the early 1930s, Rexroth became involved in the Communist party's John Reed Clubs. During this time he developed friendships with other leftist poets. In the mid-1930s, Rexroth participated in the Federal Writers' Project, and published some of his poetry in journals and little magazines. His lifelong friendship with prominent New Directions publisher James Laughlin was established at this time.
In 1938 Rexroth shifted his Communist-based political ideologies to an ecologically informed pacifism. He married Marie Kass following his first wife's death in 1940, and registered as a conscientious objector during World War II. Rexroth established a philosophy club and hosted discussion salons that attracted other West coast intellectuals and poets, and became known as the father of the Beat generation.
Rexroth received a Guggenheim fellowship in 1948 and traveled extensively across Europe and the United States. He fathered his two daughters, Katharine and Mary, by philosophy student Marthe Larsen. In addition to his weekly radio show and writings, Rexroth began to read poetry with live jazz accompaniment at popular performances. After Kass divorced him in 1955, Rexroth wed Larsen in 1958; they divorced in 1961.
In the 1960s Rexroth supported both civil rights struggles and the anti-war movement. Disassociating himself from his radical past and cultural affiliation with Beatniks and Bohemians, Rexroth became more aligned with the mainstream media and was a regular essayist for the Saturday Review and San Francisco Examiner. Rexroth received a National Institute of Arts and Letters award in 1964. He became a lecturer at the University of California, Santa Barbara (1968-1974), where he taught popular writing courses. His later poems were greatly influenced by Eastern philosophy and the work of Japanese and Chinese poets; he also became known for his poetry translations. In 1974 and 1975, Rexroth won a Fulbright to Japan and a Copernicus Award for lifetime achievement. He married his fourth wife, Carol Tinker, in 1974. He died in Santa Barbara in 1982.
Rexroth's poetry publications include: In What Hour (1940), The Phoenix and the Tortoise (1944), The Signature of All Things (1949), In Defense of the Earth (1956), Natural Numbers (1963), Elastic Retort (1973), New Poems (1974), and Flower Wreath Hill (1991). His translations include 100 Poems from the Chinese (1956), 100 Poems from the Japanese (1964), Pierre Reverdy, Selected Poems (1969), Love and the Turning Year (1970), Orchid Boat (1972), 100 Poems from the French (1972), and 100 More Poems from the Japanese (1976).
Scope and Content
The collection consists of original correspondence, manuscripts, and assorted printed materials that document Rexroth's writing, interests, and activities. Of particular note is the voluminous personal correspondence between Rexroth and close friends and family members, in addition to correspondence from major writers, poets and cultural figures, including: Ansel Adams, Homero Ardijis, Robert Bly, John Cicardi, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Morgan Gibson, Allen Ginsberg, James Laughlin, Denise Levertov, Gerard Malanga, Henry Miller, Kenneth Patchen, Edouard Roditi, William Carlos Williams, Edward Weston, and George Woodcock. The collection also includes single letters from prominent people such as Pearl S. Buck, James P. Cooney, Jack Kerouac, Ezra Pound, Man Ray, and Isaac B. Singer, among others. The manuscript series contains Rexroth's typescripts and handwritten works across several genres, including poetry, prose, translations, reviews, and his work for the Federal Writers' Project. Other series include extensive ephemera documenting the San Francisco scene, such as anti-Vietnam fliers, posters announcing readings, and event invitations; selected audio recordings of Rexroth's jazz readings and radio series; articles and clippings about Rexroth and his circle; little magazines; and Rexroth's teaching and lecture files.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975) (39 boxes), subseries A-B as follows:
A-Z, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975) (35 boxes).
Cards, 1954-1975 (4 boxes).
Esther Handler papers, 1957-1986 (2 boxes), subseries A-B as follows:
Correspondence, 1958-1986 (1 box).
Miscellaneous, 1957-1986 (1 box).
Manuscripts by Rexroth, 1922-1976 (35 boxes), subseries A-F as follows:
Book reviews, 1937-1968 (1 box).
Federal Writers Project, 1936-1939 (1 box).
Notebooks, ca. 1935-1950 (0.5 box).
Poetry and verse, 1922-1967 (9.5 boxes).
Prose, 1935-1976 (18 boxes).
Translations, 1952-1974 (5 boxes).
Manuscripts by others, 1936-1975 (18.5 boxes), subseries A-B as follows:
A-Z, 1936-1975 (17.5 boxes).
Lonergan Conference papers, 1970 (1 box).
Miscellaneous, 1925-1974 (15.5 boxes), subseries A-F as follows:
Artwork, 1941-1969 (1 folder).
Audio recordings, 1952-1966 (6 boxes).
Finances and calendars, 1947-1970 (5 boxes).
Kenneth Rexroth Books, 1940- 1957 (1 box).
Photographs, 1925-1958 (1 folder).
Travel, 1948-1974 (3.5 boxes).
Printed material, 1936-1976 (36 boxes), subseries A-F as follows:
Articles and essays, 1946-1975 (3.5 boxes).
Clippings and reviews, 1936-1975 (3 boxes).
Ephemera, 1940-1974 (10 boxes).
Little magazines, 1936-1976 (8 boxes).
Newspapers, 1938-1975 (5 boxes).
Periodicals and newsletters, 1944-1975 (6.5 boxes).
Teaching, 1953-1974 (9 boxes), subseries A-C as follows:
Lectures, 1953-1974 (2 boxes).
San Francisco State College, 1957-1966 (1 box).
UC Santa Barbara, 1968-1974 (6 box).
Related Material
Periodical articles by Rexroth are in the Little Magazine Collection (1000). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Butler, Jerry & Eager, Brenda Lee. The love we have. Chicago, Illinois: Phonogram Incorporated, 1973. 1 album (2 s.) 12 in. 33 1/3 rpm.
Two poems on the inside jacket cover are from Kenneth Rexroth's 100 poems from the Japanese. 10.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Kenneth Rexroth Papers (13 items).
Beat generation -- Archives.; Authors, American -- Archives.; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century -- United States.; Rexroth, Kenneth
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 39 boxes (19.5 linear ft.).
  Scope and Contents note
  Personal and professional correspondence. Additional letters to Rexroth may also be found as enclosures with manuscripts (see Series 4), or in his teaching and lecture files (see Series 7).
  Arranged in Subseries A-B as follows:
  A. A-Z, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975) (35 boxes).
  B. Cards, 1954-1975 (4 boxes).
  - Subseries 1A: A-Z, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 35 boxes.
    Personal and professional correspondence from various people to Kenneth Rexroth, including critics, editors, fans, poets, publishers and writers. Arranged alphabetically by surname of the correspondent, where possible. Letters from unidentified sources have been placed in folders labled "Unidentified" and filed within the "U's." For correspondence from poets regarding Rexroth's New British Poets anothology, search for the names of individual poets in this series, in addition to reviewing the New British Poets manuscript found in Subseries 3D.
    - Aarons--Abramson., 1945-1967.; 15 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academy of American Poets., 1962-1975.; 12 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Accent--Actors Ensemble., 1941-1967.; 12 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Actor's Workshop of the San Francisco Drama Guild., 1961-1965.; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adams, Ansel., 1965-1969.; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Adeane--Air India., 1935-1972.; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from Conrad Aiken.
    - Alaska Festival of Music., 1962-1964.; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alberti--Allied Artist's Council., 1946-1974.; 21 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allin--Allwood., 1941-1961.; 24 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Almadén Vineyards--American Express., 1948-1975.; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from A. Alvarez.
    - American Festival of Negro Arts--American Friends Service Committee., 1940-1967.; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Frontier Theatre--American Poetry Review., 1962-1974.; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See also Berg, Stephen.
    - American Scholar., 1969-1972.; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - American Society for Aesthetics--Amundson., 1945-1975.; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes letters from A.R. Ammons.
    - Amy Lowell Poetry Traveling Scholarship., 1958-1964.; 16 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Anagram Bookshop--Anderson, Joel., 1953-1973.; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Anderson, Lee., 1951-1965.; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Anderson, Warren--Angel Island Publications, Inc., 1947-1967.; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Anglo Overseas Transport Co.--Anvil Press Poetry., 1954-1975.; 17 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - APA-Phoenix--Approach., 1947-1972.; 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Apthaker--Ardelyan., 1955-1966.; 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Aridjis, Homero., 1972-1974.; 18 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Letters from Ardijis, Seabury Press/Continuum Books, Kenneth Rexroth, Carol Tinker, and Barbara Szerlip regarding translations of Ardijis's poems; 1 photograph of Ardijis.
    - Arena Theater--Aron., 1949-1974.; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Aronson--Art International., 1951-1964.; 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Art News--Arthur., 1951-1971.; 46 items. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Artisan--Arts Digest., 1952-1957.; 22 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Arts In Society--Ashman., 1929-1965.; 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes 1 letter from John Ashbery.
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies., 1973.; 51 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Aspen Magazine--Atlantic and Pacific Trading Co., 1960-1967.; 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Atlantic Monthly., 1963-1967.; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Atlantis Bookshop--Auerhahn Press., 1948-1966.; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Avant Garde., 1967-1968.; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Avon Books., 1965-1969.; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Axelrod, Joe and Addie., 1954-1967.; 18 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ayer, Phyllis., 1944-1945.; 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Baar--Barkan., 1951-1970.; 29 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Bard College.
    - Barker--Bartlett., 1953-1972.; 37 items. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Barton--Bay., 1949-1974.; 25 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Beach--Beck., 1950-1972.; 29 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Includes letters from Julian Beck and his Living Theatre co-director, Judith Molina; see also Living Theatre.
    - Becker--Beom., 1958-1975.; 52 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Hilary Belloc and David Ignatow (as associate editor of the Beloit Poetry Journal).
    - Berg-Bharathan Publications., 1947-1975.; 30 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from Stephen Berg and Holly Beye.
    - Bialu--Bjerknes., 1941-1970.; 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Includes letters from Earle Birney.
    - Black--Blau., 1949-1966.; 16 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blean--Blumenthal., 1948-1973.; 23 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bly, Robert., 1958-1972.; 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bobbs Merrill Company, Inc.--Bolling., 1949-1971.; 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bollingen Series--Book Service., 1950-1971.; 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from William McGuire at the Princeton University Press.
    - Books Abroad., 1972-1973.; 43 items. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Letters from Ivar Ivask regarding the Books Abroad International Prize for Literature.
    - Books and Bookmen--Bosquet., 1948-1969.; 30 items. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Boston University Libraries--Boyle., 1937-1973.; 22 items. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from Bernard Bowron.
    - Brademas--Brewer., 1953-1972.; 37 items. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from Stan Brakhage.
    - Briarcliff Junior College--British Book Review., 1944-1974.; 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation., 1959-1968.; 28 items. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Brock--BSA Sound Seminars., 1945-1973.; 49 items. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from James Broughton.
    - Buchanan--Bullins., 1948-1972.; 37 items. (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Pearl S. Buck, Edith Buis, and Edward Bullins.
    - Bunnelle--Burns., 1961-1972.; 9 items. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Burnshaw, Stanley., 1952-1974.; 44 items. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Burr--Byron., 1954-1969.; 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Witter Bynner.
    - Cabrillo Music Festival--California Writers Club., 1947-1974.; 35 items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from various state agencies.
    - Callahan--Carillon Club of Grace Cathedral., 1955-1973.; 31 items. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from the Cambridge University Press and the editor of I Think I Hear Camels Coming (little magazine).
    - Carl Cherry Foundation--Carpenter., 1953-1974.; 35 items. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Francis Carmody and Piro Caro.
    - Carr--Cayton., 1944-1970.; 38 items. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Horace R. Cayton.
    - Cebulski--Chappell., 1947-1973.; 31 items. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Brenda Chamberlain and Cathy Chapman.
    - Charles Scribner's Sons--Chicago Tribune Magazine., 1941-1973.; 35 items. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from Serge Chermayeff and the Chicago Review.
    - Childs--Chung, Kristine., 1948-1975.; 24 items. (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from the Chinese Hospital and Gordon Lish (Chrysalis West Foundation).
    - Chung, Ling., 1970-1972.; 39 items. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Church of the Advent of Christ the King--Churchill., 1961-1967.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Ciardi, John., 1954-1970.; 33 items. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      See also Saturday Review.
    - Circle--City Lights., 1946-1972.; 23 items. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from City Lights (publisher) by Lawrence Ferlinghetti, and a letter from Rexroth regarding the American Anthology.
    - Clagett--Cody's Books., 1949-1973.; 35 items. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Coffield--Combes., 1947-1972.; ca. 55 items. (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from Collier Press (regarding San Francisco: Before and After).
    - Combs, Tran., 1948-1965.; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Commentary--Commonweal., 1946-1972.; 41 items. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Commonwealth Club of California--Contact., 1945-1965.; 49 items. (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from Cyril Connolly.
    - Contemporary Literature [Cyrena N. Pondrom]--Colanovie., 1947-1974.; 20 items. (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Includes 1 letter from James P. Cooney, from Morning Star Farm, Massachusetts.
    - Corey, Ruth Lechtlitner., 1941-1973.; 19 items. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Corinth Books, Inc.--Corso., 1947-1969.; 27 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Julian Cornell (Rexroth's attorney, regarding the Harper's libel case), Cid Corman, and Gregory Corso.
    - Corwin--Coward McCann, Inc., 1948-1974.; 24 items. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cowley, Malcolm., 1941-1964.; 12 items. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cox--Creekmore., 1946-1972.; 36 items. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Creeley, Robert., 1950-1955.; 21 items. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Crehan--Crosby., 1946-1965.; 44 items. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Crossroads--Cucca Records., 1955-1969.; 27 items. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cullum--Cushway., 1947-1969.; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Includes 1 postcard from E.E. Cummings.
    - Dague--Davis., 1948-1973.; 32 items. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dawson--de Graaf., 1948-1975.; 33 items. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from the Decker Press.
    - De Jouvenel, Renaud., 1958-1967.; 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Rexroth to De Jouvenel on French literature and visiting France.
    - Delahaye--Desert., 1947-1970.; 44 items. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Deutsch, Babette., 1949-1969.; 42 items. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Deutch, Yvonne-Dick., 1953-1972.; 34 items. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Dickenson--Doss., 1941-1974.; 58 items. (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Richard Diebenkorn and Ephraim Doner.
    - Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1953-1968.; 60 items. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Dover Publications, Inc.--Dunbar., 1957-1974.; 38 items. (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Includes letters from Theodore Drenton and Raya Dunayevskaya.
    - Duncan, Robert., 1941-1958.; 27 items. (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Includes one letter from Rexroth to Duncan regarding Robert Creeley and Marthe.
    - Dunham--Dwyer., 1948-1974.; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Early Music Laboratory--Eaton., 1957-1971.; 21 items. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Eberhart, Richard., 1945-1970.; 74 items. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Ebony--Ellis., 1949-1971.; 32 items. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Ellzey--Encyclopedia Americana., 1952-1973.; 20 items. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica., 1960-1975.; 19 items. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Enders--Esquire., 1948-1975.; 30 items. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Estrin--Evans., 1951-1968.; 28 items. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from Rexroth to Pierre Abraham (Europe Review).
    - Everson, William [Brother Antonius]., 1945-1970.; 48 items. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ewig--Fact Magazine, Inc., 1948-1975.; 27 items. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from Faber and Faber publishers, and letters regarding a Rexroth article on literary criticism for Fact (editor Ralph Ginzburg).
    - Factotum--Farrell, David., 1941-1972.; 26 items. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from Elizabeth Pollet, editor, at Farrar, Straus & Cudahy, Inc.
    - Farrell, James T., 1947-1956.; 15 items. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Farrell, Marjorie--Ferguson., 1940-1974.; 35 items. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence and Kirby., 1952-1975.; 53 items. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      See also City Lights.
    - Fernandez--Fessenden., 1953-1972.; 33 items. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Fetherling--Finney., 1949-1975.; 17 items. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Firth, Germaine., 1960-1971.; 125 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - First Person--Fletcher, Frederick., 1949-1973.; 31 items. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Fletcher, John Gould., 1946-1948.; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Fletcher, William--Foothill College., 1945-1968.; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ford, Charles Henri., 1929-1959.; 33 items. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes early letters from Rexroth to Ford (editor of Blues: A Magazine of New Rhythms).
    - Ford, Hugh--Franco Colombo, Inc., 1954-1975.; 32 items. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Frankenstein--Friends of the Santa Barbara Public Library., 1946-1973.; 32 items. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Includes letter from Alfred V. Frankenstein regarding the San Francisco Opera's Jorda controversy; letters from Lilian Wolfe at the Freedom Press.
    - Fromm--Fuson., 1946-1971.; 48 items. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Gabree--Gentlemen's Quarterly., 1949-1974.; 52 items. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - George--Gibson, C. Frank., 1946-1975.; 36 items. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Gibson, Morgan., 1965-1975.; 70 items. (Box 7, Folder 11)
      See also the University of Wisconsin file for additional correspondence regarding Rexroth's appointment there.
    - Gibson, Tony--Gilston., 1945-1974.; 47 items. (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Jack Gilbert.
    - Ginsberg, Allen., 1939-1965.; 24 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis--Golden., 1949-1972.; 48 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Ralph J. Gleason.
    - Golden Goose Press--Gorlier., 1946-1972.; 63 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Mitchell Goodman and Paul Goodman.
    - Goss, Robert., 1967-1972.; 34 items. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes letters and manuscripts from Goss's research on D. Traven.
    - Gotham Book Mart--Graves, Morris., 1945-1972.; 36 items. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Bill Graham and Morris Graves.
    - Graves, Robert--Grey Walls Press., 1941-1972.; 42 items. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Includes 1 letter from Clement Greenberg, and letters from Horace Gregory and Charles Gardiner (as Chairman of the Grey Walls Press, Limited).
    - Gridley--Grougy., 1950-1975.; 23 items. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Grove Press., 1953-1967.; 56 items. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence from Donald Allen and Barney Rosset.
    - Groves--Guest., 1950-1975.; 15 items. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence from Barbara Guest.
    - Guggenheim Foundation., 1948-1966.; 51 items. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Gump's--Guyer., 1957-1968.; 10 items. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Haas--Hall., 1949-1975.; 40 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Jessica Hagedorn.
    - Hallmark Cards--Hamann., 1950-1970.; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hamalian, Leo and Linda., 1967-1974.; 21 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Hamill--Handgraaf., 1947-1972.; 10 items. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Handler, Esther., ca. 1958.; 56 items. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      General note
      For additional correspondence between Esther Handler and Rexroth, see Subseries 2A.
    - Haney--Harper, Carol., 1947-1974.; 53 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Harper and Row (Harper's Magazine)., 1953-1969.; 36 items. (Box 9, Folder 7)